# **GURJEET SINGH**

Hayes, London

Phone: 07740093490 | Email: gsgghotra@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/gsgghotra/ | GitHub: github.com/gsgghotra

Portfolio: <a href="https://bit.ly/GurjeetSingh-portfolio">https://bit.ly/GurjeetSingh-portfolio</a>

### SUMMARY

Software engineer and Computer Science graduate specialising in Advanced Web Development with Big Data. Recently completed a front-end web development bootcamp to stay at the forefront of industry trends and technologies. A strong commitment to effective communication, collaboration, and teamwork, honed during teaching experience, underpins the ability to craft visually engaging applications while also prioritising an exceptional user experience.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Frontend**: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript ES6+, Bootstrap, SASS **Backend**: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Firebase, Python

Version Control & Collaboration: Git, Github

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer (Remote)

June 2022 - Present

### **Freelance**

- Provided software applications that are built to help small businesses with their day to day tasks.
- Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using appropriate programming languages and frameworks.

# Computer Science Trainee Teacher (work placement) Villiers High School

Sep 2022 - July 2023

Southall, London, UK

- Designed curriculum units and learning materials for multiple year groups, highlighting strong collaboration and effective communication within the department.
- Enhanced departmental goals with an adaptive e-resource website, creating a more inclusive and accessible learning environment, elevating student experiences.

## **IT Support Technician**

Sep 2021 - July 2022

### **Greenford High School**

Provided essential first-line desktop support, effectively resolving technical issues, overseeing critical incidents, and managing diverse service requests.

- Efficiently set up and maintained computer labs, ensuring staff and students had uninterrupted access to essential software and resources, enhancing the user experience.
- Demonstrated a strong ability to prioritise, diagnose, and efficiently resolve incidents, following agreed-upon procedures to minimise downtime and disruptions.

### **PROJECTS**

SNEAKERSTREETS | github.com/gsgghotra/SneakerStreets | sneakerstreets.netlify.app

SneakerStreets is an innovative eCommerce platform dedicated to providing sneaker enthusiasts with a seamless shopping experience to acquire their favourite footwear.

- Contributed as ReactJs and Javascript developer and implemented basket and search features.
- ReactJs, JavaScript, React Redux, NodeJs, NPM, Vite, Bootstrap, Tailwind

HarmonyHeal is the ultimate music meditation app designed to bring tranquility and enhance your well-being.

- Contributed as Javascript developer and implemented Spotify API in the web app.
- Role: Group project
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, RESTful API, Bootstrap

### **EDUCATION**

Front-End Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: edX

Sep 2023 - Jan 2024

Certification: Pass (100% score)

Computing PGCE (Postgraduate Certificate in Education): University College London, UK June 2023

**Degree:** Pass

Computer Science BSc: Middlesex University, UK

June 2021

**Degree :** First Class Honours